# Joana Castaneda

Portfolio: <a href="https://joanacastaneda.github.io/Portfolio/">https://joanacastaneda.github.io/Portfolio/</a> Languages: English (Advanced), French (Intermediate) and Spanish (Mother tongue)



343 585-5290

dg.joana24@gmail.com

# GRAPHIC COMMUNICATION DESIGN

As a candidate, I have gained four years of experience designing for government institutions, private companies, and nonprofit organizations through various volunteer projects. I typically collaborated with the IT department as a web and graphic designer. Over these years, I have created a range of digital content, including websites, social media posts, videos, animations, banners, landing pages, logos, infographics, icons, and print materials.

#### **Education**

Attestation de formation de connaissance de la langue française Cégep de Rosemont, Montréal, QC, CA. Nov. 2023 - Nov. 2024

**Diploma, Game Programming** 2021 - 2023 St. Lawrence College, Cornwall, ON, CA.

**Degree, Graphic Communication Design** 2012 - 2016 Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, México City.

## **Technical Skills**

- Graphic design / Animation and Modeling / Digital and printed design
- Web design: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Game design: C++, Unity, Phaser
- Experienced with libraries like jQuery UI, jQuery Mobile, Bootstrap
- Use of WordPress, Wix, Figma and Canva
- Design software like Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, Audition, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, InDesign, and Blender
- Office library: Word, PowerPoint, and Excel
- Knowledge of PhoneGap, Jira and GitHub
- Knowledge of SEO practices

# **Work Experience**

## **Graphic / Web Designer**

October 2023 – January 2024

**ACOMM** / (Freelance project to renovate a website for an organization in Montreal)

 Design a prototype in Figma for the latest version of some sections of the website ACOMM taking into consideration the values of the organization.

#### **Graphic Designer Volunteer**

July 2023 – October 2023

**BTSADV /** (Volunteer for a nonprofit organization who helps women in USA)

- Elaborate flyers and invitations for events, promotions, and awareness of BTSADV.
- Create designs, concepts, and posts for social media.

Martin's Inn / (Part time and eventual job at Hotel in Ontario Canada during my time as a student)

- Attend customers, check online reservations verifying data.
- Provide and ensure that customers receive good quality service at any given time.
- Attended the requests of customers to ensure a positive experience during their stay.
- Assist with food preparation, cooking, cleaning, and sanitizing the workspace.
- Managing inventory and organizing items to ensure adequate supplies.

# Web and Graphic Designer

2017 - 2021

**Tax Administration Service** / (government institution in Mexico)

- Updated the website's applications with new sections and content.
- Designed new applications which answer to the needs of each department.
- Optimized the main portal website making it easier for the employees to find the information to complete their activities on time.
- Created digital content for the needs of the institution like videos, tutorials, banners, landing pages, infographics, icons, presentations, and posts for social media.
- Dealt with the lack of communication between different areas creating alerts in the systems and sending a news section through the email.
- Stimulated the working environment with the suggestion of designing videos to show appreciation for the accomplished goals of the employees.

# Web designer

July 2017 – October 2017

We R Unlimited / (Web Agency in Mexico City)

- Contributed to the development of a website for the Genuino Metco company designing a clean and friendly interface (https://www.metco.com.mx/).
- Design of 6 mini-sites: AzucarBC, Svetia, Mascabado, DBsugar, Piloncillo and Sweet-0.

#### **Graphic designer**

2016 - 2017

**Goros Lotu** / (*Transport Company in Mexico City*)

- Established an image more coherent and clearer designing digital and printed material.
- Optimized prices in printing materials and negotiating with the suppliers the best options.

## **Soft Skills**

- Effective communication, I try my best to listen and be clear to avoid misunderstandings in any task.
- **Positive attitude**, I perform my activities with kindness and respect.
- Time management, I have experience of knowing what to prioritize and organize.
- Responsible, I do the tasks assigned with professionalism and with the values of the company.
- **Creative**, I like to think of options and ideas to improve the service.
- Team worker, I enjoy working in a team.